# **Mohamed Hamdy**

Cairo, Egypt | 00201114763285. Riyadh, KSA 00966 582724731 | hamdy2855@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

With computer science background and technical knowledge, I have a proven experience **as SAP ABAP/ Workflow/ Web Dynpro Consultant for about 6 years** handling a lot of projects in and outside Egypt, and had worked on wide range of functional areas like (PM, CS, RE, MM, SD, HCM, FICO, QM and Healthcare)

# **Work History**

- 1- SAP ABAP/Workflow/Web Dynpro Consultant | Smart Consulting Solutions | 05/2016 to 10/2019.
- 2- SAP Senior ABAP/ Web Dynpro Consultant | Electronic Government Authority (EGA) | Ras Al Khaimah Government (RAK) | Egypt Office | 11/2019 to 01/2020.
- 3- SAP Senior ABAP/Workflow/DMS Consultant | INNOVATECH | 02/2020 to 10/2020.
- 4- SAP Senior ABAP /DMS Consultant | Atos | 11/2020 to 08/2022
- 5- SAP Senior ABAP/ Workflow Consultant | Johnson Controls | Saudi Arabia Office (Al Salem Johnson Controls) 09/2022 to Current
- Besides coding and developing a SAP modules' customizations, I am performing a number of other tasks, some of which are given below:
- Consulting with professionals from other departments and those working on specific SAP modules such as SAP FI/CO, MM, HR, PM, PP, Healthcare and CS to ensure a consistent experience to the various users on the client's side.
- Writing the code using ABAP programming language based on the blueprint provided by the clients and performing regular tests on the usability of the code.
- Providing technical support to the end users in the form of troubleshooting guidelines and modifications to the system after it has been delivered.
- To stay updated with the latest technological advancement and changes in the world of SAP development and adapting to these changes by self-training and research work.
- AS DMS Consultant I am responsible for the setting up of the DMS and Document Lifecycle covering documents types
- · Also, as DMS Consultant I am handling integration with other modules thru object linking, version management and document structure.

## **Skills & Abilities**

#### **TECHNICAL**

- · Modularization Techniques.
- · Data Dictionary.
- · ALV Reports.
- · Smart Forums.

- · BAPIs.
- · 00P.
- · Enhancements

- · Adobe forms
- · Dialog programming
- · Workflow
- · Web Dynpro
- · OData SAP Gateway
- · Batch Data Communication
- · SAP Reporting Tools (ABAP Queries, Ad-Hoc Query, Quick Viewer)
- · UI5 with WEB IDE (Entry Level)
- · Healthcare-PMD
- · SAP DMS

# **Projects**

#### 1. Abou Ghaly Motors.

- o Automotive
- o ABAP Consultant

#### 2. Al-Mishari Hospital-KSA

- o HealthCare
- o ABAP Consultant and ISH shadowing Consultant

## 3. Egyptian Steel (outsourcing 9 months)

- o Steel Manufacturing
- o ABAP Consultant

#### 4. IGI

- o Real state
- o ABAP Consultant

#### 5. Al Akkad Hospital

- o HealthCare
- o ABAP Consultant

#### **6. Shatta** (Fabrics&Curtains)

o ABAP Consultant

#### 7. Rajhi-KSA

- o Real state
- o ABAP Consultant

#### **8. IOderat** (Service Solution)

o ABAP Consultant

#### 9. SCS Rental Car-UI5 (Service Solution)

- o ABAP-UI5 Consultant
- o Not completed yet

Click here to view the application (you can login with your SAP ID)

#### 10. Comprehensive investigation-EGA-RAK

- o Governmental-Land Sector
- ABAP-WEB DYNPRO Consultant

#### 11. Namma Construction

o SAP DMS Consultant

### 12. Egypt Gas

- o Public Sector
- o SAP ABAP / DMS Consultant

# **Education**

## **6th of October University**

· Major: Computer Science

· Year: 2015

## **Additional Information**

Skype: hamdy2855@outlook.com

Date of Birth: 1 January 1993

**Mother Tongue:** Arabic

Other Languages: English (Very Good spoken and written)